tddirectinvesting.co.uk 2016-11-23

# Privacy Policy - TD Direct Investing

We are committed to providing you with the highest quality service. This includes maintaining your privacy and protecting your personal data. In addition to the Customer Terms of Service the following policy explains what we and our associated companies in the TD Bank Group do with the personal data we collect about you. We will tell you which companies are in the TD Bank Group upon request. Our contact details are at the end of this privacy policy. To get the best from our services, please keep your personal data (including your email address) accurate and up to date. You can do this by choosing; Account Administration, Personal Details after logging into our secure website or by contacting us at the address or telephone number given at the end of this policy.

Please take the time to read this privacy policy carefully. In opening an account with us you consent to our use of your personal data in accordance with the Customer Terms of Service and the TD Privacy Policy. We hope that by implementing and operating this policy, we will make your online experience a more secure and enjoyable one.

**Contents**

  1. Why have a privacy policy?
  2. What personal data do we collect about you and how?
  3. How do we use your personal data?
  4. Safeguarding your personal data?
  5. What are cookies and how do we use them?
  6. Sale of the business
  7. Contacting us

**1: Why have a privacy policy?**   
There are a number of laws which set out important standards regarding information that identifies a living individual. This is known as "personal data." All organisations processing personal data must do so fairly and lawfully. They must also be registered or "notified" with the Information Commissioner whose role it is to ensure that organisations comply with their data processing obligations. If you wish, you can view a copy of our data protection notification by visiting the Information Commissioner's website. For example certain rules apply to sending direct marketing information by certain methods such as telephone and email. At TD we treat all of our obligations seriously and take all steps necessary to comply when we store and process your personal data.

Top

**2: What personal data do we collect about you and how?**   
It is essential to us to collect, store and process your personal data so that we can offer and perform our services. Some of the information we request is voluntary, and you do not have to provide it. Typical information we might ask for includes your name, your address, other contact details and bank account information. We may also store other personal data, including information from third parties, such as credit referencing agencies.

In addition our servers automatically receive and record information on all visitors to our websites. Please see section 5 (below) about cookies for more information.

We will only hold your personal data (aside from the automatic information detailed above) once you have been issued with a registered username and password, and your registration with our services has been completed.

We collect your personal data in a number of different ways, including the following:

  * if you provide it when communicating with us (For example when registering for our services);
  * if you order any of our products or services;
  * if you enter a competition or promotion;
  * if you make payments or modify your account details; and
  * when you visit our websites (for example by cookies and other browser-generated information).

Top

**3: How do we use your personal data?**   
We retain and use your personal data for the following main purposes:

  * Naturally we reserve the right to access and disclose your personal data if we are required to do so by law (or if we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law), or if it is necessary for the proper operation of our systems, the protection of TD or its users and customers, or for the enforcement of our Customer Terms of Service.

  * processing applications made by you, running your accounts, providing our services, contacting you and servicing our relationship with you; administration and accounting, billing and auditing and other legal purposes;
  * security, payment verification, preventing and detecting money laundering, fraud and other crime, insurance, credit assessment and administration, tracing debtors and recovering debt. For these purposes, we may also pass on your personal data to third parties;
  * generating statistics on our users, such as the popularity of certain of our services, about the "traffic" visiting our websites. When we do this, your data becomes anonymous and you are not personally identified; and
  * disclosing your Personal Information with any other TD Bank Group Companies or any of our agents, including data processors, in the United States of America or Canada or other jurisdictions in or outside the European Economic Area who may only use it for the same purposes as us.

Except where you have not agreed to be contacted for example by using the declaration section on the application form or you have written to us asking this we may also use your personal data to keep you informed about relevant products and services. We may use your personal data including your contact details, your application details (but not banking details) and details of the services we provide you with and how you use them, to decide what products and services may be of interest to you. We may contact you by telephone (including automated calls), post, email and other electronic messages such as short text, video and picture messaging, and fax, with information, news, events and seminars on our investment, banking and financial services and those of TD Bank Group and other selected partners. Please click here for details of our products and services.

We may also pass this information to companies in the TD Bank Group and selected partners for them to contact you about their products and services in the same ways. You can ask us at any time to stop sending you this information by writing to us at the address at the end of this policy. Please remember that even if you have requested this, we may still contact you about the running of your existing account and for the services requested from us.

Top

**4: Safeguarding your personal data**   
We take all reasonable care in the collection, storage, processing and disclosure of your personal data and have implemented internal security procedures so as to minimise the risk that unauthorised parties will be able to access the information. It is because of these security procedures that we may ask for proof of identity before we disclose any personal information about you. Only certain TD employees and contractors have access to your personal data and although we cannot guarantee that your information will never be lost, misused or altered by any of our employees, we have implemented procedures to minimise the risk of these unlikely events.

Nonetheless, the Internet is an open medium and we cannot guarantee that any information you send to us by email or via our website will not be intercepted or tampered with. To help protect your personal data and minimise the risk of it being intercepted by unauthorised third parties our secure servers employ industry standard Secure Socket Layer v3 (SSL) or Transport Layer Security v1 (TLS) encryption when you submit information to us through our website. This security is signified by the "https" and the padlock on the URL bar. Some older browsers do not allow the use of current SSL technology and we therefore recommend that you use an up to date browser for example Microsoft Internet Explorer 8.0 or above.

You can also help to protect your personal data, by following the guidelines below:

  * choose a password that you will be able to remember but that would be hard for someone to guess. Ideally it should include special characters (such as "?" or "#" for example) and numbers. We recommend that you change it regularly and if you need to write it down, always keep it in a safe place;
  * make sure that no-one can see the details you are entering when you log-in;
  * if other people have access to your computer, remember to close your browser each time you log-off and end your session and, if possible, clear any history of the websites you have visited and that your browser may have saved or "cached"; and never disclose your account details to anyone.

For more information and top tips please visit the security pages of our website.

Top

**5: What are cookies and how do we use them?**   
Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and allows us to improve our site. For more detailed information on the cookies we use and the purpose for which we use them see our Information About Cookies page.

Top

**6: Sale of the business**   
In the event that the TD business is sold fully or in part, integrated with another business, or it disposes of its rights and obligations under any agreement with you, your records may be disclosed under appropriate confidentiality terms to our advisers and any prospective purchasers' adviser, and will be passed onto the new owners.

Top

**7: Contacting us**   
Please bear in mind that this privacy policy only applies to websites and services operated by TD and not those operated by third parties, including those to which our websites may link. We suggest that you make yourself familiar with any privacy policy operated by third party websites before providing personal information about yourself.

You are entitled to a copy of the personal data we hold about you on payment of a small administration fee. If you would like to see this information, please write to the address below.

Data Protection Officer  
TD Direct Investing  
Exchange Court  
Duncombe Street  
Leeds  
LS1 4AX

Or, if your query is about your TD Bank N.V. Savings account you may write to:

Compliance Officer   
TD Bank N.V.  
Strawinskylaan 1103,  
1077 XX Amsterdam,  
Netherlands

If you have any queries about this privacy policy, any of the Customer Terms of Service or the website in general, do not hesitate to contact us:

Customer Service Manager  
TD Direct Investing  
Exchange Court  
Duncombe Street  
Leeds  
LS1 4AX  
Tel: 0345 607 6001  
Email: [customer_services@tdwh.co.uk](mailto:customer_services@tdwh.co.uk)

Top
